Guide to the Derrick A. Bell, Jr. Papers MC.138
New York University Archives
- Accession 2017-016: Course Materials and Books, 1922-2011; 1988-2011
  Arrangement
  This series has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
  - Constitutional Law Spring 08, 2007-2008 (Box 169, Folder 1)
  - Hypo 2: Articles I and II: Separation of Powers, 2007-2008 (Box 169, Folder 2)
  - Hypo 3: Article I: Commerce Clause, 2007-2008 (Box 169, Folder 3)
  - Hypo 5: Federalism, 2007-2008 (Box 169, Folder 4)
  - Hypo 6: Dormant Commerce Clause, 2007-2008 (Box 169, Folder 5)
  - Hypo 7: Article IV: Full Faith and Credit Clause, and Wachowski v. Matrix General Hospital, 2007-2008 (Box 169, Folder 6)
  - Hypo 8: 5th Amendment: Takings and Eminent Domain, 2007-2008 (Box 169, Folder 7)
  - Hypo 9: 5th and 14th Amendments: Substantive Due Process, 2007-2008 (Box 169, Folder 8)
  - Hypo 10: 5th and 14th Amendments: Procedural Due Process, 2007-2008 (Box 169, Folder 9)
  - Hypo 11: 5th and 14th Amendments: Due Process for Non-Citizens, 2007-2008 (Box 169, Folder 10)
  - Hypo 12: 8th Amendment: Cruel and Unusual Punishment, 2007-2008 (Box 169, Folder 11)
  - Hypo 13: 14th Amendment: Equal Protection (Rational Basis with Teeth), 2007-2008 (Box 169, Folder 12)
  - Hypo 14: 14th Amendment: Equal Protection (Sexual Orientation), 2007-2008 (Box 169, Folder 13)
  - Hypo 15: 14th Amendment: Equal Protection (Intermediate Scrutiny), 2007-2008 (Box 169, Folder 14)
  - Hypo 16: 14th Amendment: Equal Protection (Strict Scrutiny), 2007-2008 (Box 169, Folder 15)
  - Hypo 17: 14th Amendment: Equal Protection (Fundamental Rights -- Voting), 2007-2008 (Box 169, Folder 16)
  - Hypo 18: 1st Amendment: Free Speech Basis, 2007-2008 (Box 169, Folder 17)
  - Hypo 19: 1st Amendment: Prior Restraint and Hate Speech, 2007-2008 (Box 169, Folder 18)
  - Hypo 20: 1st Amendment: Freedom of Association and Privacy, 2007-2008 (Box 169, Folder 19)
  - Hypo 21: 1st Amendment: Obscenity, 2007-2008 (Box 169, Folder 20)
  - Hypo 22: 1st Amendment: Defamation, 2007-2008 (Box 169, Folder 21)
  - Hypo 23: 1st Amendment: Free Exercise Clause, 2007-2008 (Box 169, Folder 22)
  - Hypo 24: 1st Amendment: Establishment Clause, 2007-2008 (Box 169, Folder 23)
  - NYU 2008-2009 (Box 169, Folder 24)
  - Hypo 34: EFF v. Obama: Articles I and II Powers, State, Secrets Doctrine, 2008-2010 (Box 169, Folder 25)
  - Hypo 7: University of Texas v. U.S.: Congressional Power -- Spending, 2008-2010 (Box 169, Folder 26)
  - Hypo 9: Wachowski v. Matrix General Hospital et al -- Full Faith and Credit Clause, DOMA, 2008-2010 (Box 169, Folder 27)
  - Bell Spring CRT Seminar, 2010 (Box 169, Folder 28)
  - Hypo 2: Graham v. U.S.: 8th Amendment: UWOP, 2010 (Box 169, Folder 29)
  - Hypo 1: National Popular Vote Compact, 2010 (Box 169, Folder 30)
  - Constitutional Law Spring 2010 Photos (Box 169, Folder 31)
  - Constitutional Law '10 Class Notes, 2010 (Box 169, Folder 32)
  - Constitutional Law '10, 2010 (Box 169, Folder 33)
  - Hypo 5: Kiyemba v. Obama: Article II -- Executive Power, 2010 (Box 169, Folder 34)
  - Hypo 6: Full Faith and Credit DOMA, 2010 (Box 169, Folder 35)
  - Hypo 6: Direct TV, Inc. v. Lexin -- Dormant Commerce, 2010 (Box 169, Folder 36)
  - Hypo 20: Mariana Abrams: Equal Protection (Intermediate Scrutiny), 2010 (Box 169, Folder 37)
  - Hypo 21: Arcadia v. James: 1st Amendment: Free Speech, 2010 (Box 169, Folder 38)
  - Hypo 22: IMS Health and Sorrell: 1st Amendment -- Commercial Speech, 2010 (Box 169, Folder 39)
  - Hypo 23: Courtney Love: 1st Amendment: Defamation, 2010 (Box 169, Folder 40)
  - Hypo 24: Arizona Life Coalition v. Stanton: 1st Amendment (Government), 2010 (Box 169, Folder 41)
  - Hypo 25: U.S. v. Stevens: 1st Amendment -- Animal Cruelty, Obscenity, 2010 (Box 169, Folder 42)
  - Class Photos, 2010 (Box 169, Folder 43)
  - Hypo 26: CLS v. Martinez: 1st Amendment -- Freedom of Speech, Association, Free Exercise, 2010 (Box 169, Folder 44)
  - Hypo 13: McDonald v. Chicago: Privileges and Immunities Clause (2nd Amendment), 2010 (Box 169, Folder 45)
  - Hypo 14: CRR and Planned Parenthood v. Arcadia: Substantive Due Process, Abortion Rights, 2010 (Box 169, Folder 46)
  - Hypo 15: Rasul v. Rumsfeld: 5th Amendment (Due Process, Constitutional Right not to be Tortured), 2010 (Box 169, Folder 47)
  - Hypo 16: Doe v. Klein: Procedural Due Process, Sex Offender Registry, 2010 (Box 169, Folder 48)
  - Hypo 17: Fisher v. University of Texas: Equal Protection: Affirmative Action, 2010 (Box 169, Folder 49)
  - Hypo 18: Orliss v. Oregon: Equal Protection: Same Sex Marriage, 2010 (Box 169, Folder 50)
  - Hypo 19: Parents Opposed to Income-based Assessments or Challenge to Healthcare Reform Bill, 2010 (Box 169, Folder 51)
  - Hypo 3: Salzar v. Bouno: 1st Amendment (Establishment Clause, 2010 (Box 170, Folder 1)
  - Hypo 8: Chicanos Por La Causa v. Napolitano -- Supremacy Clause, Pre-Emption, Arizona Immigration Case, 2010 (Box 170, Folder 2)
  - Manual of Supplements and Suggestions for Race, Racism, and American Law, 1990 (Box 170, Folder 3)
  - Slavery and Poverty, 1988 (Box 170, Folder 4)
  - Jewish Americans Student Paper, 1990 (Box 170, Folder 5)
  - Constitutional Issues Case Reports, 1991 (Box 170, Folder 6-7)
  - Extra Credit and Finals, 1997 (Box 171, Folder 1)
  - Constitutional Issues Class Docket, Briefs, and Bench Memos, 1999 (Box 171, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlets, 1923-2011 (Box 171, Folder 3)
  - Books, 1962-2004 (Box 172, Box 173, Box 174)